Srinivasan Chakkarapani

Digital Product Designer (UI-UX)

www.srinivasan.design +1 312-973-6557

tcsreeni93@gmail.com

Summary

A passionate full spectrum product designer with 3 years of experience designing and shipping digital products for multiple companies in Food Tech, FinTech & SaaS platforms. I'm an advocate for functional, aesthetic and user centered products which has an impact on people's life solving a need. I have a strong belief that a good product is a concoction of design and technology.

Education

Master of Science, Human Computer Interaction

DePaul University, Chicago - May 2020 (Expected)

Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science & Engineering

SASTRA University, India - May 2015

Professional Experience

Interaction Designer, Zeta

February 2018 - August 2018

Worked on two stealth mode products bundled inside the Zeta Optima product which focuses on digitising the tax benefits for employers & employees on both web and mobile platforms. Initiated & framed a design system for products across web and mobile platforms.

Product Designer, Zoho Corporation

December 2015 - January 2018

Designed and shipped the Zoho Sheet product as the primary product designer. As a principal designer, I worked on the application's mobile platforms (i.e.) on the iOS, Android platforms from ideating features, wireframing to setting visual standards and framing a design system. Worked closely with the developers, Product managers to effectively ship the product to the respective application stores which onboarded many web application users to the mobile platforms.

Product Designer, Holachef

June 2015 - December 2015

Designed the iOS and Android Application for the company. Wore the hat of web designer in designing the primary web product. Also helped in designing various back end applications that helped in the functioning of the business.

Key Skills

Information Architecture

Contextual Inquiry

Wireframing

Interaction Design

Visual Design

Prototyping

Motion Design

Usablity Testing

Design Systems

Mobile Design

Web Design

Low/ High fidelity mockups

User Research

Tools

Wireframing

Balsamiq, Axure RP

Design

Sketch, Adobe Photoshop & Illustrator, XD, Figma.

Prototyping

Principle, Adobe After Effects, Framer X, Marvel, Invision.

Development

HTML, CSS, Javascript.

Activities

Student Member at the Depaul XD RoundTable